Guide to the George Adams Shuford Papers, 1952-1959
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
George Adams Shuford papers 1952-1959
Shuford, George Adams
Extent: 36,000 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.01182
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The George Adams Shuford Papers were gifts to Duke University in 1959 and 1968.
Biographical Note
George Adams Shuford (b. 1895) served North Carolina as a lawyer, jurist, state legislator, and member of Congress. He was educated in the public schools of Asheville, the University of North Carolina, and the Law School of the University of Georgia. In 1932 he married Daphne Brown of Asheville. His public career included service as Representative in the State Legislature, 1945-1947, and U. S. Representative, 1953-1959. After retirement from Congress, he became a Superior Court Judge of North Carolina from which he returned to the practice of law in Asheville.
Collection Overview
Shuford's papers consist of 89 boxes of correspondence, reports, speeches, and memoranda from his office in Washington, 1952-1959. The collection is divided into four main categories according to the filing system used in the Congressman's office. Subjects, persons, and places appear throughout all categories.
The Shuford Papers were in filing drawers when originally cataloged. Later the papers were transferred to many smaller archival boxes. Since it was no longer easy to survey the contents, an informal inventory of the files was compiled by a student assistant. The collection remains in its original folders with their informal and frequently inconsistent labeling.
The correspondence has two divisions. First, there are letters filed alphabetically by names of correspondents (Boxes 1-21). However, each letter of the alphabet also has one or more folders in which the correspondence is filed only according to the first letter of the name. Secondly, there are letters filed chronologically in folders marked Letters. Legislation (Boxes 22-23) and Letters. General (Boxes 24-28). There are also several folders of letters of congratulations, recommendations, references, and sympathy (Box 28).
Volumes of guest books and an inaugural invitation (1953) are in Box 28.
Speeches and speech material are in Boxes 29-30.
Subject categories occupy Boxes 31-89. The folders are labeled and are filed according to the words underlined on each label. The labeling system was not consistent, and researchers must survey the subject categories for a given subject as well as the correspondence and speeches. Subjects notable for the quantity of material about them are: agriculture, the armed services, atomic energy, elections, civil rights, civil service, Colorado River, commerce, the Constitution, the Democratic Party, education, electric power utilities, finance, fish and wildlife, foreign relations, highways, Indians, the House Interior and Insular Affairs Committee, irrigation and reclamation, labor (often under education and labor), the judiciary, mines and mining, politics in North Carolina (especially the 12th congressional district for which there are election records on the precinct level), the Post Office, public lands, refugees, small business, the House Ways and Means Committee, tariffs, taxation, TVA, tobacco, veterans affairs, the Territories Subcommittee (Alaska and Hawaii), and water resources.
The chronology within folders is frequently out of order. The letters are not entered in the Autograph File.
2,000 Items added, 1-3-68. This addition to the subject categories of the Shuford Papers is notable for files on the Blue Ridge Parkway, the Cherokee Indians, and the Hell's Canyon Legislation.
Subject Headings
Democratic Party (U.S.); Tennessee Valley Authority; United States. Congress -- Committees; United States. Congress -- Elections; Agriculture -- Law and legislation; Civil rights -- United States; Civil service -- United States; Education -- United States; Electric utilities -- Law and legislation -- United States; Indians of North America -- Government relations; Labor laws and legislation -- United States; Land use -- Law and legislation -- United States; Legislators -- United States -- Correspondence; Mining law -- United States; North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1951-; Nuclear energy -- Government policy; Public lands; Roads -- Finance -- Law and legislation -- United States; Tariff -- Law and legislation -- United States; Taxation -- Law and legislation -- United States; Tobacco -- Law and legislation -- United States; United States -- Armed forces; Commerce -- United States; United States -- Constitution; United States -- Economic conditions -- 1945-; United States -- Foreign relations -- 1945-; United States -- Politics and government -- 1953-1961; Veterans -- Law and legislation -- United States; Water resources development -- Law and legislation -- United States; Wildlife conservation -- Law and legislation -- United States
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series
  - Ainsley, John Joseph (Box 1)
  - Alberts, J.C. (Box 1)
  - Alice, James A. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Raymond D. (Box 1)
  - Alley, John Hayes (Box 1)
  - Allison, J.Q. (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Lionel C. (Box 1)
  - Angel, Marie (Box 1)
  - Arkansas, John P. (Box 1)
  - Armistead, Nancy C. (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Mrs. Leslie Ray (Box 1)
  - Arrowood, Gordon C. (Box 1)
  - Ashe, Gene E. (Box 1)
  - Atkins, Bobby Ju (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Jack (Box 1)
  - Austin, William H. (Box 1)
  - A (Box 1)
  - A (Box 1)
  - Bach, Robert J. (Box 1)
  - Bagby, James (Box 1)
  - Ballew, Harry S. (Box 1)
  - Balsam Grove Hospital (Box 1)
  - Banks, Victor S. (Box 1)
  - Barclay, Thomas, IV (Box 1)
  - Bartlett, William W. (Box 1)
  - Bates, Clyde T. RDI (Box 1)
  - Batten, W.T. (Box 1)
  - Beachboard, William B. (Box 1)
  - Beardall, Harold M. (Box 1)
  - Beasley, James E. (Box 1)
  - Beatty, Coy R. (Box 1)
  - Beerkens, Johannes Wilhelmus (Box 1)
  - Bemis Lumber Co. Land (Capt. Swann) (Box 1)
  - Bene, Doris (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Ada (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Thomas James (Box 2)
  - Biddle, Roy. Franklin, N.C. Mining Lease Nan. Nat. For. (Box 2)
  - Bileb, F.B. Annie Laurie (Box 2)
  - Bishop, Mrs. Letha (Box 2)
  - Blaak, Kommer (Box 2)
  - Blake, Edmund M. (Box 2)
  - Blake, Nick (Box 2)
  - Blankenship, Wade (Box 2)
  - Bocook, Jas. Fulton (Box 2)
  - Boone, Dix. Macon County (Box 2)
  - Boukides, Andreas P. (Box 2)
  - Bourne, Francis. MICZ (Box 2)
  - Bowen, Robt. A. (Box 2)
  - Bowman, Peter W. (Box 2)
  - Boyd, James R., Jr. (Box 2)
  - Bradburn, C.F. (Box 2)
  - Bradford, Ronald D. (Box 2)
  - Bradley, Earl (Box 2)
  - Brady, Robert (Box 2)
  - Brank, Brad. Veteran (Box 2)
  - Branson, Bertrum L. (Box 2)
  - Brezeale, Willard J. (Box 2)
  - Bridges, Charles G. Arden, N.C. (Box 2)
  - Briggs, James Frank (Box 2)
  - Brigman, Wilburn L. (Box 2)
  - Bristol, Dave (Box 2)
  - Brittain, Airman Joseph A., Jr. (Box 2)
  - Brittain, J.A. (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Mamie Rae (Box 2)
  - Brookshire, C.M. 359671 (Box 2)
  - Brookshire, Wm. E.B. (Box 2)
  - Brown, Al (Box 2)
  - Brown, Bob (Box 2)
  - Brown, Claude (Box 2)
  - Brown, Dr. George Wallace (Box 2)
  - Brown, J.C. Veterans Adm. Employee (Box 2)
  - Brown, Perry (Box 2)
  - Brown, Robert (Box 2)
  - Bryan, John (Box 2)
  - Bryant, Segal W. (Box 2)
  - Bryson, Carl E. (Box 2)
  - Bryson, Holmes Jr. (Box 2)
  - Bryson, L.D. (Box 2)
  - Buchanan, Ben (Box 2)
  - Buchanan, Marcellus (Box 2)
  - Buckner, Dorothy Messer (Box 2)
  - Bugg, Wm. J. (Box 2)
  - Bunch, Willie (Box 2)
  - Bunker, Ruth E. (Box 2)
  - Burleson, Earl. Re: Tobacco Division (Box 2)
  - Burleson, Joe (Box 2)
  - Burnette, Fred M. (Box 3)
  - Burson, John H., Jr. (Box 3)
  - B (Box 3)
  - B (Box 3)
  - Cabe, Lester (Box 3)
  - Calloway, Bruce James (Box 3)
  - Cameron, Betty (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Harry (Box 3)
  - Capps, Ralph (Box 3)
  - Capps, Walter C. (Box 3)
  - Carland, Stanley J. (Box 3)
  - Carr, Frank Brown (Box 3)
  - Cassada, Wiley (Box 3)
  - Cathey, Dan (Box 3)
  - Chaney, Walter Elick and B.P. Justice (H'ville) (Box 3)
  - Chaponan, Max H. (Box 3)
  - Chasteain, Oscar E. (Box 3)
  - Cheatwood, William E. (Box 3)
  - Christenson, Harry J. (Box 4)
  - Chung, P.N. 2-1375 (Box 4)
  - Clement, Latta (Box 4)
  - Clodfelter, Hobert Dalton (Box 4)
  - Clowney, Lillie (Box 4)
  - Cobb, Julia S. (Box 4)
  - Cochran, John C. (Box 4)
  - Collins, Joe W. (Box 4)
  - Combe, B.A. (Box 4)
  - Cooley, Cong. Attorney J.M. Brougloth, Jr. HR. 8381 (Box 4)
  - Cooper, Mrs. Lola A. (Box 4)
  - Corn, Floyd Lee (Box 4)
  - Cornwell, D.W. (Box 4)
  - Cotter, John R. (Box 4)
  - Cotter, John R. (Box 4)
  - Courtesy of the Port (Box 4)
  - Cox, Mrs. Ella (Box 4)
  - Crawford, Lester (Re: Road, Burmingtown and Kyle Section (Box 4)
  - Crawford, Warvel J., Jr. (Box 4)
  - Crawford, Mrs. J.M. (Box 4)
  - Creasman, Stella (Box 4)
  - Creasman, Maleta M. (Box 4)
  - Cross, Arthur H. (Box 4)
  - Cullowhee College (Box 4)
  - Cunningham, John R. (Box 4)
  - Cutshall, John E. (Box 4)
  - C (Box 4)
  - C (Box 5)
  - Dacy, Kenneth (Box 5)
  - Dale, Charles (Box 5)
  - Dalton, Carl V. (Box 5)
  - Damtoft, Walter (Box 5)
  - Davenport, Mr. and Mrs. Shelton (Box 5)
  - Davidson, Jas. E. (Box 5)
  - Davis, Dee (Box 5)
  - Davis, Harry Mc. (Box 5)
  - Davis, Lt. Col. James M. Hazelwood, N.C. (Box 5)
  - Davis, Watts (Box 5)
  - Dayton, Jas. E., Jr. (Box 5)
  - Dayton, Harolotis (Box 5)
  - Dayton, Mrs. Olga H. (Box 5)
  - Deacon, Edward F. (Box 5)
  - Deane, Charles B. (Box 5)
  - DeMoia, Miss Josephine (Box 5)
  - Deyton, Claude (Box 5)
  - Dillingham, Watson (Box 5)
  - Dillingham, Woodrow (Box 5)
  - Dolan, Thes. E. (Box 5)
  - Dotson, Icesom N. (Box 5)
  - Drigian, Krikor (Box 5)
  - Dunlap, Herbert M. (Box 5)
  - D (Box 5)
  - D (Box 6)
  - Earle, Willie L. (Box 6)
  - Edens, James E. (Box 6)
  - Edwards, Chas. W., Jr. (Box 6)
  - Eller, Elizabeth (Box 6)
  - English, Guy (Box 6)
  - Ensley, Wm. (Box 6)
  - Ervin, Sen. Sam J. (Box 6)
  - Ervin, Saumuel E. (Box 6)
  - Evans, Robert Lee (Box 6)
  - E (Box 6)
  - E (Box 6)
  - Farmer, Private Garland (Box 6)
  - Farmer, Robert (Box 6)
  - Farmer's Market, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Ficken, Lt. Harry A. (Box 6)
  - Finlay, Bill. Tax Case (Box 6)
  - Fisher, Ernest M. (Box 6)
  - Fitzgerald, Jerry M. (Box 6)
  - Fleischman, Miron (Box 6)
  - Foard, Carson C. (Box 6)
  - Foate, Allen M. (Box 6)
  - Foster, Uless C. (Box 6)
  - Foster, Wm. L. (Box 6)
  - Fox, Arthur J. (Box 6)
  - Fox, Gilbert Coil (Box 6)
  - Francis, A.J. (Box 6)
  - Freeman, Calvin W. (Box 6)
  - Friday, James W. (Box 6)
  - Friedlander, Egon Chas. (Box 6)
  - Frisk, Paul W. (Box 6)
  - Fritschy, Philip H. (Box 6)
  - F (Box 6)
  - F (Box 7)
  - Galloway, Earl F. (Box 7)
  - Galloway, Ray von (Box 7)
  - Garcia, Blavlio (Box 7)
  - Garren, Alvin W., Jr. (Box 7)
  - Garren,Benjamin F. (Box 7)
  - Garrett, Robert U. (Box 7)
  - Garrett, Thomas Wade (Box 7)
  - General (Box 7)
  - Gennett, Andrew (Box 7)
  - George, Pvt. Charles. Congressional Medal of Honor Winner. Feb. 6,1954 (Box 7)
  - George, Ida J. (Box 7)
  - Glasby, Willie C. (Box 7)
  - Glendale (Box 7)
  - Glover, Fred W. (Box 7)
  - Godwin (Box 7)
  - Goins, Robert T. (Box 7)
  - Goodman, L.J. (Box 7)
  - Gosnell, Amar (Box 7)
  - Graham, Billy (Box 7)
  - Grant, Roger (MICA Matter) (Box 7)
  - Grant, Mrs. Roger (Box 7)
  - Greene, Mrs. A.W. (Box 7)
  - Greene, F. Lynette (Box 7)
  - Green, yard (Box 7)
  - Greenleaf, Wm. F (Box 7)
  - Gregg, George (Box 7)
  - Gregg, Ray S. (Box 7)
  - Gregg, Samuel (Box 7)
  - Gregory, Mrs. Lyman (Box 7)
  - Griggs, James Y. (Box 7)
  - Grimsley, Rollie L. (Box 7)
  - Grohar, Albin (Box 7)
  - Gudger, Lindsey M. (Box 7)
  - Guggenheim, Warren E. (Box 7)
  - Guice, Robert Ronald (Box 7)
  - Gulledge, Otis U. (Box 7)
  - G (Box 7)
  - G (Box 8)
  - Hagglund, Irvin A. (Box 8)
  - Hall, L. Dow. Deceased (Box 8)
  - Hall, Pvt. Eddie R. (Box 8)
  - Hall J.B., Jr. (Box 8)
  - Hall, Shuford M. (Box 8)
  - Hall, Wm. J. (Box 8)
  - Hamm, Pvt. Thomas H. (Box 8)
  - Haney, Charlie Arthur (Box 8)
  - Haney, James M. (Box 8)
  - Harmon, Cleo Davis (Box 8)
  - Harris, Mrs. Ethel Mary George (Box 8)
  - Hawkins, Charles C. (Box 8)
  - Hayes, Lewis (Box 8)
  - Hayes, Pearl (Box 8)
  - Hayes, Terry Lee (Box 8)
  - Haywood Lumber and Mining Co. (Box 8)
  - Hazelrigg, Charles H. (Box 8)
  - Hefner, Mrs. Frances B. (Box 8)
  - Henderson, Frank B. (Box 8)
  - Henderson Rev. J.H. (Box 8)
  - Hennessee, W.W. Small Business Loan Application Request (Box 8)
  - Hensley, John C. (Box 8)
  - Hepler, Carrie W. (Box 8)
  - Herbert, Mrs. John T. (Box 8)
  - Herren, Claude Luther (Box 8)
  - Hess, W.T. Neal (Box 8)
  - Hester, William D. (Box 8)
  - Hilliard, Howard (Box 8)
  - Hitchner, C.E. (Box 8)
  - Hodges, Daniel M. (Box 8)
  - Hodges, Luther H. (Box 8)
  - Hoffman, Edwin M. (Box 8)
  - Holt, Gerald W. (Box 8)
  - Hornbuckle, Israel C. (Box 8)
  - Howard, Clarence, Jr. (Box 8)
  - Howell, James S. (Box 8)
  - Howell, J. H. (Vet's Service Officer Haywood County) (Box 8)
  - Howell, Moody A. (Box 8)
  - Howerton, T.M. (Box 8)
  - Huddle, T.A. (Box 8)
  - Hudspeth, Geo L. (Box 8)
  - Hunter, Susan (Box 9)
  - Hurley, Wade McCoy (Box 9)
  - Hyde, B.J. (Box 9)
  - H (Box 9)
  - H (Box 9)
  - Inman, Harry (Box 10)
  - Internal Revenue Office. Asheville (Box 10)
  - Irvin, Mrs. Grace S. (Box 10)
  - I (Box 10)
  - I (Box 10)
  - Jaeckel, Vrs. Louis E. (Box 10)
  - James, Walter (Box 10)
  - Justice, Private Joe (Box 10)
  - Jenkins, Wm. E. (Box 10)
  - Jennings,A1 (Box 10)
  - Johnson, Carl E. (Box 10)
  - Johnson, Carl E. (Box 10)
  - Johnson, D. Byers (Box 10)
  - Johnson, John J. (Box 10)
  - Johnson, Richard C. (Box 10)
  - Johnson, Ulysses, Jr. (Box 10)
  - Jones, Bruce C. (Box 10)
  - Jones, Pvt. Ralph M. (Box 10)
  - J (Box 10)
  - J (Box 10)
  - Kdan, Stephen (Fed. Housing Loan) (Box 10)
  - Keener, Ernest (General) (Box 10)
  - Kelly, Rev. Richard A. (Box 10)
  - Kennerly, Dr. R.B. (Box 10)
  - Kennett, Franks., Jr. (Box 10)
  - Kent, Mrs. E.L. (Box 10)
  - Keritsis, Constantinor D. (Box 10)
  - Keritsis, James (Box 10)
  - Kilby, Harvey (Box 11)
  - Kilmer, Kenton (Box 11)
  - Kilpatrick, Emeline (Box 11)
  - Kimsey, Sgt. Willard (Box 11)
  - Kimsey, Willard, Corp. (Box 11)
  - King, William (Box 11)
  - Kuykendall, Marvin A. (Box 11)
  - K (Box 11)
  - K (Box 11)
  - Lamb, Mrs. Bobra White (Box 11)
  - Lambert, Paul (Box 11)
  - Langbein, John Frederick (Box 11)
  - Laughrun, Ray J. (Box 11)
  - Lawing, Enoch A. (Box 11)
  - Le Febera, Anthony (Box 11)
  - Leinster, Robert O. (Box 11)
  - Lewis, William A., Jr. (Box 11)
  - Lindley, Mrs. Jas. J. (Box 11)
  - Lipe, Albert (Box 11)
  - List, Keith Eugene (Box 11)
  - Littlefield, Mrs. Russell R. (Box 11)
  - Locke, William L. (Box 11)
  - Logan, Sam J. (Box 11)
  - Long, John Adrian (Box 11)
  - Long, Pat (Box 11)
  - Lotspeich, Wm. B. (Box 11)
  - Lowery, Florenee C. (Box 11)
  - L (Box 11)
  - L (Box 11)
  - McCall, Donald Lee (Box 12)
  - McCall, Pvt. James C. (Box 12)
  - McCloskey, David, Jr. (Box 12)
  - McCormack, Cpl. Joe H., Jr. (son of Mrs. Alonso) (Box 12)
  - McCoy, Stella (Box 12)
  - McCrary, Wester N. (Box 12)
  - McCurry, Herbert E. (Box 12)
  - McDavis, Floyd E. (Box 12)
  - McElrath, Moody (Box 12)
  - McGaha, Oscar (Box 12)
  - McHan, Beauford, Pfc. (Box 12)
  - McKinnish, Lloyd M. (Box 12)
  - McClean, Albert S. (Box 12)
  - McRary, William (Box 12)
  - Maconochie-Vance Gap Road (Box 12)
  - McTammary, Mrs. John (Billie) (Box 12)
  - Mc (Box 12)
  - Mc (Box 12)
  - Mackelfresh, Mrs. Robert H. (Box 12)
  - Maney, Buron R. (Box 12)
  - Maney, Forrest R. (Box 12)
  - Maney M./Sgt. Wm. Jack (Box 12)
  - Mann, Mrs. G.P. Re: Visa for Mother (Box 12)
  - Martin, Bill (Box 12)
  - Martin, Jack (Box 12)
  - Martin, John W. (Box 12)
  - Martin, Sesto (Box 12)
  - Maultsky, Ben H. (Box 12)
  - Mauney, Betty (Box 12)
  - Mauney, Harry (Box 12)
  - Mauney, Walt (Box 12)
  - Means, Butler C. (Box 12)
  - Medford, Cecil (Box 12)
  - Melton, C.A. (Box 12)
  - Messer, Jennie D. (Box 12)
  - Metzger, Mrs. Nina (Judge Shuford's Cousin Re: birth certificate) (Box 12)
  - Miles, Herbert (Box 12)
  - Miller, David Lee (Box 12)
  - Miller, Paul R. (Box 12)
  - Miller, Richard (Dick) (Box 12)
  - Millsaps, Maynard (Box 12)
  - Mitchell, Dewey (Box 12)
  - Mitchell, Gene P. (Box 12)
  - Mitchell, James E. C-11 279 676 (Box 12)
  - Montgomery, Elzabad (Box 13)
  - Moody, Warren K. (Box 13)
  - Mooney, Mrs. Charles (Box 13)
  - Moore, Charlie L. (Box 13)
  - Moore, Mrs. George H. (Box 13)
  - Moore, Meredith (Box 13)
  - Morgan, Dwight L. (Box 13)
  - Morgan, Harley D. (Box 13)
  - Morgan, Robt. K. (Box 13)
  - Morrow, Tommy Mac (Box 13)
  - Mull, Mrs. Rosalie (Box 13)
  - M (Box 13)
  - M (Box 13)
  - Nailling, Dr. Richard C. (Box 14)
  - Nash, Forrest F. (Box 14)
  - Nelms, William (Box 14)
  - Nelon, Bud (Deceased) (Box 14)
  - Nelson, Sidney V. (Box 14)
  - Newman, Mrs. P.B. (Box 14)
  - Nicely, Mrs. R.V. (Box 14)
  - N (Box 14)
  - N (Box 14)
  - O'Donnell, Ed (Box 14)
  - Oliver, Helence Perryman (Box 14)
  - Oshborne, Henry D. (Box 14)
  - Oskinski, Connie Jeane (Box 14)
  - Osmeña, Sergio, Jr. (Box 14)
  - O (Box 14)
  - O (Box 14)
  - Pagan, Pvt. Bruce T. (Box 14)
  - Palat, Nicholas E. (Box 14)
  - Palmer, Leonard (Box 14)
  - Parker, Wm. C. (Box 14)
  - Parks, James H. (Box 14)
  - Pastell, Mrs. Mozelle B. (Box 14)
  - Pastell, Ray (Box 14)
  - Peacock, Dorothy B. (Box 14)
  - Penland, Elwin M. (Box 14)
  - Perkins, R.F. (Box 14)
  - Peters, Robert G. (Box 14)
  - Peters, Robert G. (Box 14)
  - Peterson, James R. (Box 14)
  - Peterson, O.B. (Box 14)
  - Pettit, 1st Sgt. William B. (Box 14)
  - Phelps, Mrs. Barbara H. (Box 14)
  - Pike, James M. (Box 14)
  - Pilkington, Daniel D., Pvt. (Box 14)
  - Pisgah Forest School (Box 14)
  - Pistolis, George A. (Box 14)
  - Plemmons, Joe E. (Box 14)
  - Plott, William M. (Box 14)
  - Posey, Horace G., Jr. (Box 14)
  - Posey, R.Y. (Box 14)
  - Powell, Charles (Box 14)
  - Powell, Dr. Charles H. (Box 14)
  - Powell, William Hugh (Box 14)
  - Pressley, James N. (Box 14)
  - Pridgen, Mrs. Eva L. (Box 14)
  - Prock, James Paull (Box 15)
  - Proctor, Mrs. H.L. (Box 15)
  - Proctor, Schwartz (Box 15)
  - Putnam, Robert J. (Box 15)
  - P (Box 15)
  - P (Box 15)
  - P (Box 15)
  - Quality Tire Company, Inc. (Box 15)
  - Quinn, Charlie H. (Box 15)
  - Q (Box 15)
  - Ramsey, William D. (Box 15)
  - Ray, Avon I. (Box 15)
  - Ray, Robert E. (Box 15)
  - Rayburn, Joe Hubert (Box 15)
  - Rayle, Champ G. (Box 15)
  - Reagan, Mrs. Phlenia M. (Box 15)
  - Redden, Arthur J. (Box 15)
  - Rector, Doris L. (Box 15)
  - Redmon, James C. (Box 15)
  - Reed, Miss Edith B. (Box 15)
  - Reese, Harry L. (Box 15)
  - Reichenfeld, Hilde (Box 15)
  - Rein, Stewart (Box 15)
  - Reynolds, James C. (Box 15)
  - Reynolds, Wm. F. (Box 15)
  - Rice, James L. (Box 15)
  - Rich, Ronald (Box 15)
  - Roberts, David (Box 15)
  - Roberts, Everette (Box 15)
  - Roberts, Frank Monroe (Box 15)
  - Roberts, Raymond Henry (Box 15)
  - Robertson, Dr. Logan (Box 15)
  - Robey, Mrs. Eunice E. (Box 15)
  - Robinson, Charles (Box 15)
  - Robinson, Clarence O. (Box 15)
  - Robinson, E.L. (Box 15)
  - Robinson, Rufus (Box 15)
  - Robinson, Thomas Calvin (Box 15)
  - Rocamora, Fan B. (Box 16)
  - Rockwell, Kenneth (Box 16)
  - Rodenbeck, Frederick L., Jr. (Box 16)
  - Rogers, Rep. Dwight (Box 16)
  - Rogers, Ernest (Box 16)
  - Rogers, Jack, Jr. (Box 16)
  - Rogers, Raymond (Box 16)
  - Romfh, Bros. Transylvania County. Jack Potts, Fisher, Anthony (Box 16)
  - Roper, Gano N. (Box 16)
  - Roth, John Wm. (Box 16)
  - Rouland, Paul C. (Box 16)
  - Russell, Eva R. (Box 16)
  - R (Box 16)
  - R (Box 16)
  - Sams, Jack Garrett (Box 16)
  - Sams, Jack G. (Box 16)
  - Sawyer, Jimmy (Box 16)
  - Sawyer, Holmes (Box 16)
  - Scales, A. H. (Box 16)
  - Schoeler, Ernest P. (Box 16)
  - Schulz, Theodore and Annie (Box 16)
  - Searcy, David M. (Box 16)
  - Sentelle, R. E. (Box 16)
  - Shaw, Ralph A. (Box 16)
  - Sherlin, Richard B. (Box 16)
  - Shuford, John (Box 16)
  - Silvers, Mr. (Box 16)
  - Silversteen, Joseph A. (Box 16)
  - Simmons, George C. (Box 16)
  - Simpson, Capt. David, Jr. (Box 16)
  - Singleton, Mrs. James E. (Box 16)
  - Smathers, Charles (Box 16)
  - Smathers, Henry C. (Box 16)
  - Smathers, Max M. (Box 16)
  - Smith, Charles D. (Box 16)
  - Smith, Clive H. (Box 16)
  - Smith, Mrs. Donald (Box 16)
  - Smith, J. B. (Box 16)
  - Smith, Kenneth E. (Box 16)
  - Solomon, Rufus C. (Box 16)
  - Staffen, Clarence F. (Box 16)
  - Stallings Air Base (Box 16)
  - Stamey, Ella Owen (Box 16)
  - Stamey, James D. (Box 16)
  - Stamey, Wilford (Box 16)
  - Stephens, Hugh (Box 16)
  - Stepp, Claude (Box 16)
  - Stepp, J.F. (Box 16)
  - Stevens, A/3c S.E. (Box 16)
  - Stevenson, H.A. (Box 16)
  - Stines, Ernest Harrison (Box 16)
  - Stone, Clarence M. (Box 16)
  - Stone, Wallace B. (Box 16)
  - Strauss, Karl H. (Box 16)
  - Streadwick, Cecil L,. (Box 16)
  - Swan, Frank. Small Bus. Loan. (Box 16)
  - Sweeny, Stanley W. (Box 16)
  - S (Box 18)
  - S (Box 18)
  - Tahlguetle, Dewey (Box 18)
  - Taliaferro, Walter R. (Box 18)
  - Talley, Bailey T. (Box 18)
  - Taylor, Jos J., Jr. (Box 18)
  - Taylor, Joseph J. (Box 18)
  - Tennent, Dr. G.S. (Box 18)
  - Thacker, Add (Box 18)
  - Thomas, Blanche A. (Re: retirement) (Box 18)
  - Thompkins, Archie (Box 18)
  - Thompson, Harry Zebulon (Box 18)
  - Thompson, Ralph M. (Box 18)
  - Toland, Hugh James, Jr. (Box 18)
  - Trull, Ed F. (Box 18)
  - Trull, Rupert L. (Box 18)
  - Turner, Myrtle N. (Box 18)
  - T (Box 18)
  - T (Box 18)
  - U (Box 18)
  - Vaughan, Wanda Marie (Box 18)
  - V (Box 18)
  - Walden, Earl W. (Box 20)
  - Walker, William Pitt (Box 20)
  - Walsh, T.I. (Re: Scholarship for son, Homer Jerome) (Box 20)
  - Walton, Mrs. Kester (Box 20)
  - Walton, Dr. Seth T. (Box 20)
  - Ward, Guy A. (Box 20)
  - Watts, Bob (Box 20)
  - Wayman, Mrs. Bessie E. (Box 20)
  - Weather Station (Box 20)
  - Weather Wing Employment (Box 20)
  - Weaver, William J., III (Box 20)
  - Webb, Grady C. (Box 20)
  - Weber, Mr. and Mrs. Anton. and Sister Ingeborg (Box 20)
  - Weeks, Mrs. Maude Sanders (Box 20)
  - Welch, Virgil (Box 20)
  - Weissinger Lumber Company (T.M. Jenkins. Atty) (Box 20)
  - Weissinger Lumber Company (Box 20)
  - Weissinger Lumber Company (Box 20)
  - Wells, Nellie L. (Geo. W.) (Box 20)
  - Western Carolina Livestock. Dept. of Agriculture (Box 20)
  - Wheeler, Clyde H. (Box 20)
  - Whitaker, Ed. B. (Box 20)
  - White, Morris H. (Box 20)
  - White Transportation Co. (Box 20)
  - Whitmire, Howard (Box 20)
  - Whitner, Bobby M. (Box 20)
  - Whittemore, Orville A. (Box 20)
  - Wilder, Mrs. Mary E. (Box 20)
  - Wildes, Robt. Eugene (Box 20)
  - Willis, Thomas W. (Box 20)
  - Wilson, Bobby Ray (Box 20)
  - Wilson, Charles G. (Box 20)
  - Wilson, Morris (Box 20)
  - Wilson, Mrs. Nellie (Box 21)
  - Wimpey, Bennis Howard (Box 21)
  - Wolfoy, John (Box 21)
  - Wood, Mrs. Essie (Box 21)
  - Woodard, Mrs. Charlie (Box 21)
  - Woodson, Marvin C. (Box 21)
  - Woody, Walker Western (Box 21)
  - Worley, Dan C. (Re: over-seas employment) (Box 21)
  - Wright, Neva C. (Box 21)
  - Wrinn, Mrs. John Jones (Box 21)
  - W (Box 21)
  - W (Box 21)
  - Yarborough, Lonnie P. (Box 21)
  - Yost, M.F. (Box 21)
  - Young, Donald (Box 21)
  - Young, Fred R. (Box 21)
  - Young, Luther H., Jr. 01-647 010 (Box 21)